# Kent Kai-hsiung Chang Curriculum Vitae

kai-hsiung.chang.17@ucl.ac.uk

https://kentchang.com/

SUMMARY Kent Chang's research focus is on applying text mining techniques and natural language processing to cultural texts to address literary-historical inquiries at scale.

Kent is a fully-trained digital humanist with a relevant MSc degree from UCL. He has worked for the British Library, creating web-based services to promote and facilitate text mining for humanities research. He is affiliated with .txtLAB at McGill University and a registered researcher

# of HathiTrust Digital Library.

Kent holds a BA degree in English, specialising in nineteenth- and twentieth-century literature and culture. He also has significant teaching experience: before UCL, he taught English for seven years; at UCL, he has organised a study **group** on cultural and literary text mining, where he has been giving lectures and teaching Python, to address the lack of coverage on relevant topics in UCL's DH curriculum.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University College London, London, UK

[September 2017–present]

MSc in Digital Humanities (degree expected October 2018)

- 2017/18 student academic representative
- thesis: "Literary Modelling Queer Modernity: Interpretations and Inferences of Anglo-American Queer Novels, 1860–1923" (supervisors: Dr Julianne Nyhan and Dr Luke Dickens)

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

[September 2014–June 2017]

BA in Foreign Languages and Literatures (linguistics and literatures in English)

## University of Taipei, Taipei, Taiwan

[September 2011–August 2014]

BA program in English Instruction (TESOL), double major in Computer Science; transferred to National Taiwan University in September 2014

#### **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING AND SCRIPTING LANGUAGES

Python, JavaScript (including jQuery and React.js), R, PHP, C/C++, Java

MARKUP LANGUAGES

HTML5 and CSS3 (including Bootstrap 4 and GRAPHIC, AUDIO, AND VIDEO EDITORS Sass), XML (including XSLT 2.0 and TEI-P5), LATEX, Markdown

#### NATURAL LANGUAGES

Mandarin Chinese (native), English (fluent), German (proficient), Classical Latin (intermediate), Japanese (beginner)

Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, AfterEffects, and Audition

## RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Research assistant and researcher

[July 2018–present]

.txtLAB at McGill University

(supervisor: Prof. Richard Jean So)

parsing and analysing digital archives of HathiTrust Research Center

## Workplacement/intern, Research Services

[July 2018-present]

The British Library

(supervisor: Simon Moffatt)

creating a web app for researchers to query and download the Library's textual resources; writing Python tutorial series in Jupyter